<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Adelina&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://blog.adelinachau.com/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Adelina&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 30 Oct 2022 17:19:14 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.adelinachau.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Being a Girl in STEM: My Experience</title>
      <link>https://blog.adelinachau.com/posts/girlinstem/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Oct 2022 17:19:14 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.adelinachau.com/posts/girlinstem/</guid>
      <description>Being a Girl in STEM is not easy.
Whether it&amp;rsquo;s being the only girl in an advanced computer science class, teaching web development to a room full of 35 students most of whom are guys, or being the only girl on my school&amp;rsquo;s computer science club leadership, I have grown fairly accustomed with my place in the male-dominated field — most of the time at least.
Being a girl in STEM can often be a very isolating experience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Quantum Hype</title>
      <link>https://blog.adelinachau.com/posts/quantumhype/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Oct 2022 12:18:42 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.adelinachau.com/posts/quantumhype/</guid>
      <description>If you&amp;rsquo;re anything like me, you&amp;rsquo;ve probably heard the term quantum computing thrown around more lately.
But, what&amp;rsquo;s with all the hype around quantum computing?
Quantum computing harnesses quantum mechanicsal phenomena to perform computation, so before we go into the nitty gritty details of all quantum computing has to offer, there&amp;rsquo;s a few fundamental quantum mechanical concepts we need to understand. Let&amp;rsquo;s rewind a few decades and see how all this started:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stars Over Yosemite</title>
      <link>https://blog.adelinachau.com/posts/stars-over-yosemite/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 08:51:59 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.adelinachau.com/posts/stars-over-yosemite/</guid>
      <description>The first time I went stargazing was at the age of 15, which is rather late compared to most people. A good reason for this might be thanks to the fact that I live in a pretty big city, hence light pollution is a real big issue.
Don&amp;rsquo;t get me wrong. I love the urban suburban vibe where I live, but it really isn&amp;rsquo;t ideal for stargazing. Here, staring up at the sky at even the darkest times of the day only allowed me to see a handful of stars, so growing up, thats how I thought things were–just a few stars here and there randomly scattered across the sky.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
